Louis Lourens VAN DER BIIL

Software engineer

Contact No: 060 526 1031

Email: lourensvdbijl@gmail.com LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lourensvan-der-bijl-453a6a19b

Website:

https://lourens-online.netlify.app/

Professional summary.

Upcoming BSCIT graduate offering competitive software engineering skills across multiple platforms. I am experienced in object-oriented programming, developing, testing and debugging, UI/UX, SQL, and networking. My education proof that I am a quick self-study student that can produce outstanding results.

Relevant Skills

- Source control / version control
- Networking
- Databases
- Information systems UI/UX
- Management information systems
- Object-oriented coding
- Fluent in English and Afrikaans
- Driver License
- **Cloud Computing**
- Multiple IDE's knowledge

Coding Skills

- HTML & CSS (HTML5 & CSS3)
- **JavaScript**
 - Bootstrap 0
 - **JOuerv**
 - **VUE.JS** 0
 - AmChart.is 0
 - **Ajax**
 - PHP
- VB.net
- C++
- SQL

Soft Skills

- Critical out of the box thinking
- Problem solving and logical thinking attitude
- Team leading abilities
- Team player
- Great time management
- Self-motivated
- Excellent communication skills
- Creative
- Fast learner
- Passionate coder

Education.

Richfield Graduate Institute of Technology

(BSCIT)

Currently enrolled at Richfield Graduate Institute of Technology as a second year distance student with outstanding results in all my subjects in my Bachelors Degree of Science in Information Technology (Majoring development)

- Result can be viewed at: https://lourens-online.netlify.app/education.html
- One of the top student of my group.
- Obtaining 3+ distinction per semester.
- Semester year 2 semester 3 achieved distinctions in all BSCIT subjects.

Technology High School Middelburg

(National Senior Certificate)

Complete date: 2012-12 National Senior Certificate obtain at Technology High School Middelburg class of 2012.

- Testimonial can be viewed at: https://lourens-online.netlify.app/education.html
- Subjects:
 - Afrikaans 0
 - **Enalish**
 - Mathematics 0
 - Computer Application Technology

- o Business Studies
- Geography
- Life-orientation studies

SOLOLEARN

SQL Fundamentals course

(Online Learning platform)

Complete date: 2020-07

Complete date: 2021-12

These certifications do not provide any additional credits. The goal of completing these certificates was to show my dedication and interest in the development field and also to gain some additional knowledge of these subjects.

Course:	Date Complete:	<u>Certificate Link:</u>
HTML Fundamentals course	19 July 2020	https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1014-15586817/pdf/
CSS Fundamentals course	24 July 2020	https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1023-15586817/pdf/
JavaScript Tutorial course	19 July 2020	https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1024-15586817/pdf/

25 July 2020 PHP Tutorial course

https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1059-15586817/pdf/ 27 July 2020 https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1060-15586817/pdf/

Work Experience

mySHEQ.com

(Junior JavaScript Developer Freelance)

Employed as a trainee part-time JavaScript developer at mySHEQ.com, an easy to use health and safety applications for all health and safety requirements.

- Immigrate from Amchart 3.js to Amchart 4.js.
- Development of an anti-cheat browser software for test writing purposes.
- Research of Vue.js for future coding solutions.

Umbane Technology

(Network Operations Supervisor)

Date: 2017-01 to Present

Date: 2020-09 to Present

Employed as a Network Operations Supervisor / Team leader at Umbane Technology, a networking contractor company for multiple ISP.

- Worked closely with network administrators and server engineers to deliver quality service.
- · Planned layouts and ran cable into buildings and through walls, attics and crawl spaces.
- Diagnosed and resolved complex integrated customer issues for implementation, add-on, maintenance and support of voice, data, VoIP and CTI applications.
- Installed and configured new devices and system components.
- Performed network operations and installation of telecommunication equipment for several telecom companies.
- Responded to service requests during and after business hours.
- Maintained excellent attendance records, consistently arriving to work on time.
- Managed quality assurance programs, including on-site evaluations, internal audits and customer surveys.

Umbane Technology

(Assistant Supervisor)

Date: 2014-01 to 2017-01

Employed as an assistant Supervisor / Assistant Team leader at Umbane Technologies.

- Aid Site Supervisor in day to day team management activities.
- Assist with daily site operations and quality control.
- Assist in configurations of network equipment.
- Assist with surveys and installation documentation.
- Provide training to junior staff members.
- Standby driver.
- Obtain a perfect attendance records consistently arriving to work on time.
- Risk assessor

Umbane Technology

(Network operations Technician)

Date: 2014-01 to 2017-01

Employed as a Network technician at Umbane Technologies

- Fall arrest technician.
- Rope access practitioner.
- First Aider.
- Fire Fighter.
- Quality installations and upgrades of network equipment.
- Conducting of on-site surveys.
- Maintain top quality of installations and upgrades.
- Perfect attendance records consistently arriving for work on time.

Voluntary work experience

- Provide Web application templates for Umbane Technologies.
- Provide Symmetric decryption training for Cell City MTN mobile dealership.
- Provide coding assistance to fellow BSCIT students

View my online profile at: https://lourens-online.netlify.app/

GitHub Account:

https://github.com/LourensVanDerBijl